and with that I'm just gonna try and do
where am I
I need to find where I am on Twitter so
that I can post this and there we are
watching this on Twitter and you want to
participate on camera then you can
follow the link in the comments and if
you are on YouTube you can follow the
link in the description
hopefully it updated hopefully doesn't
still say we're doing this as 6 to 6:30
yeah this is what day is it sad day 5 at
the quarantine but stay fly with me
doing this possibility during the
pandemic I feel like I've had a fairly
good 24 hours I talked to Jordan hall
yesterday which was exactly what I
needed both will get too much into it
it's on the youtube channel you can
watch the whole thing but I feel more
empowered in my mission to bring the
global tech solutions cooperative to the
world that that is exactly what the
world needs right now and how we're
doing that is through solution raising
so is this all about I'm creating a well
we are creating a tech cooperative so
that we can create the infrastructure to
be able to come together on a massive
scale this was we were doing this before
Cove in nineteen but now that everyone's
stuck inside it gives us an opportunity
to reach more people have more people
join because although tech is something
that only a talented group it takes it
takes education it takes knowledge know
how to build the tech but everyone can
have a say in what we want that tech to
look like what we want our version of
Facebook to look like if we had a social
media platform that was designed for us
to come together for Kovan 19 what would
that look like if we knew this pandemic
was happening a year from now what would
we be putting in place so that we could
better help with our mental and
emotional health right now better
coordinate that we know our food systems
are going to continue better coordinate
experts being able to share information
with one another so that this thing gets
dealt with with the best information
possible how what would we want our
politicians to be doing and how would we
be holding them accountable what kind of
technology could we create and so I've
been speaking about it for a while what
the power of a tech cooperative without
feeling like I've been giving it the
communication it deserves because people
here Tech and they glaze over it is like
I don't know text text the enemy not not
the solution and so I did a video series
in December called together tech it's on
this channel and then we have our own
channel together Tech where we're
actually building the cooperative we
have our live board meeting live median
staffing and just three over three and a
half hours I'm doing this every day
coming on from 8:30 to 9:30 nine time
Pacific Standard Time to work on
creating the solution raising part of
the tech cooperative together so over
the last two months we've been hosting
solution reasons we've done them on six
different topics a solution raising is
simply an hour-long conversation that
generates potential solutions that we
could actually implement right now if we
had 10,000 people and $100,000 and lived
in the world we currently live in so we
can't necessarily pass laws we can't
necessarily enforce our views on other
people nor should we be able to but we
can create a solution for the 10,000
people who want that solution and so
after talking to Jordan Holly yesterday
and he'd get him giving me his advice on
what that would look like and I will be
sitting with that for the next few days
two weeks and figuring out Cogan
individual on a community level well we
right now it's hard to do because who
would need to do that as Google in our
governments and we are seeing what the
lack of trust in those institutions is
costing us all there's both correct
information that were not listening to
and false information that we are
listening to and who knows which is
which who knows our governments are the
best we have right now to deal with us
and they are in no way adequate to deal
with it so if we had a technology
cooperative that we owned together that
was our version of Google then we could
have designed it in a way but we felt
comfortable giving our data so as soon
as this hit we could be taking our
temperature every day and putting it
into a database we could be coming up
with our own tests for hope at 19 and
would it be as great is what they're
trying to come up with maybe not but it
would be something we could be sharing
that information so that next year
sharing that information I have a bit of
a mess here but you know the problem is
I click on the link on your YouTube
video and YouTube videos still playing
so I hear kind of an echo with the group
of people I'll have it open yeah it
looks like it's a gorgeous place to go
for a walk it's not like another single
human being I mean I think I can hear
your kin so or no are you with your kid
maybe it was me the YouTube I don't know
how oh yeah you know available because
he might start crying anyway hi someone
had asked M HR had asked what do we have
any ideas which policy that China
followed what are your thoughts like
right now with or authoritarian
government
Korean governments and what the
potential is with both of those and
could we have a option that gave us the
best of both worlds interesting question
I mean politics is a hard topic for me
I tend to avoid it I don't know maybe me
like many others have political PTSD
we're trying to find the safe space be
able to talk about it without hurting
anyone's feelings but I don't know as a
Swiss person I have a bias for
decentralization which is the way I mean
we have like our central government
decides a few things but our so-called
Canton's I don't know how you would call
them maybe counties or something have a
lot of power legislative powers and so
we have we see many experiments at the
local level and then the ones that work
well get adopted at the federal level
and so I think there is power in that
approach it's kind of like Nassim Taleb
uses Switzerland as an example for
antifragility right because because of
that because you can do experiments and
some of them will fail in central
authority is that the central authority
needs to make the right decisions if
they do then it's very efficient if they
don't then I mean basically that's the
problem right with fragility right if
you have a benevolent king that is super
smart and that's the best government you
can have that's the fragility right if
that person becomes mad then you have a
problem who don't want any King in
charge of us and even if the King is
enough planting Pines and does the exact
right thing we want to do the opposite
because we have oppositional disorder
stay inside I'll show you inside where
is it we ask Jordan Peterson kind of
questions like who follows the king
right when the King dies okay yeah
absolutely it's true 270 conversation on
how like Harvard and Yale and mie I
don't know maybe a mighty still has its
clout but you know a generation ago it
was the top people who went there
now although it was always the case now
it's even more so that it's basically
the alumni of people who are successful
the last generation like it's like that
your parents were successful doesn't
actually mean you're successful and you
paid for your place and it's the same
with with King succession right if we
are raised in to royalty and you that
can be a positive at can you can get all
the leadership skills that you need in
order to be able to do that but chances
are you didn't happen to be everything
you need to be to be a good benevolent
leader yeah I don't know my sense is
like I have a very you know rough idea
of what good politics are is yeah it's
just I my biases towards again like an
individual action etc which is not to
say that it's always the right approach
it's just the way my brain works right
like for example I I I keep thinking
about Wikipedia right Wikipedia now
nobody would think of funding like
asking governments to provide an
encyclopedia you know like it's just a
joke right now we have Wikipedia we
don't need any government to do that
so that's kind of my kind of bias right
let's try to find the solutions that
made a centralized solution obsolete you
probably have a similar bias yes yes
like and this is where we're seeing for
wind Koba 19 hit China they were able to
deal with it in a much more efficient
manner than Canada in America in
Australia but I don't want that
efficiency like I don't want to give up
what I wouldn't give up to get that
efficiency and at the same it becomes
more and more clear that there is this
trade-off between efficiency and
resilience right I wanted to ask you
another thing that's not exactly related
but in your talks with people did you
talk about what kind of application or
technology could be helpful right now
like something that could be built
within a few days
or so you know I'm asking as a weather
engineer which is kind of part of the
issue I find is someone who's you know
likes tech thinks tech can save the
world but isn't no way tech a little bit
of a technophobe is that a one I don't
necessarily know what's easy to code
right but I have an idea that if it's
one or two three word features in it
it's probably easier to code then of
course like dozens of features that I'll
have to interpret but and that's kind of
the question where if we knew this
company miracle now what would we want
to have in place and I think those
things the things that take six months
to build the things that take a year to
build are actually the more powerful
ones they might they won't help
necessarily with hope in nineteen but
this is our baby apocalypse like as much
as it's not going to be a baby in many
many many countries we're going to see
mass devastation it's kinder than
climate change and it's literally doing
the exact same thing the poor more
affected foreign countries and the poor
countries are more affected like what
would we want to have had in place if we
knew this was going to happen in a year
and then start creating those things for
the next I'm sorry I have to interrupt I
have to leave right now so if anyone
wants to come and join me on camera
again the link is in the description in
YouTube and on periscope you'd have to
go to my Twitter and follow the comments
I commented on this stream and that
comment is the link to come and to come
and join on camera but you can think
about what would if you had the option
of giving your data into a data pool
that we could use to know how where this
is spreading and how and how much
whether your genetics makes you more
susceptible to it whether you're what
you're eating and what you're doing is
prevention is going to actually help
prevent it because you don't you don't
know unless you're part of a population
you could do everything right and still
get sick and you could do everything
wrong and not get
that cannot and and not and you're not
going to know that the things you're
doing or helping or not unless it's part
of the population or you can see what it
is and so places like China can demand
your information Google can't they might
under this because of the the UM what is
the word the direness of the situation
might be able to do things they wouldn't
be able to do in a normal in normal
times but we're still not gonna feel
great about it if because google has our
phones they actually have you can see
information that is coming out that is
more washed data like look we can see
that everyone's still traveling we can
see who's doing social distancing who's
not doing social distancing in counties
in in states because of course it's all
American that the data there they're
showcasing in the media and there was I
remember two weeks ago there was a map
of there's a smart thermometer and they
get the data back and so they were they
can actually see when there's about to
be an outbreak of flu before other
people because they can see the places
where the temperatures are increasing in
our bodies and Florida was red it was
during spring break in Florida was red
and the rest of the country wasn't and
we're I mean seeing what else is is
going on if we had access to that type
of information so that we could better
like what's the word we had our
infectious disease solution raising and
part of what we had come up with that we
could do a ten thousand people and a
hundred thousand dollars and that's one
might be a little far-fetched because
how do those knows it's back to that
much money to great now but to be able
to use existing technology like Google
Maps like our cell phones in a way that
we feel safe in a way that's safe enough
and be able to to share in that data so
that if you were doing something like
taking zinc or melatonin or vitamin C is
that going to help you have a better
outcome if you get this are you if
you're it's really hard to know who's
asymptomatic and has this but when you
get it and you get a positive test
what was your information over the last
two weeks three weeks where do we think
you got it from and we can see
everywhere you've been and it could
paint everybody's phone who's also been
in those locations and during that exact
period
because it doesn't hang out in the air
for very long so you don't need like
right now there's this heightened first
of all everywhere so you can't even
track who has it who doesn't have it
like it's just not really that helpful
now to track when you there's a positive
case everyone they've come in contact
with because really I just saw a post
yesterday I was like yeah that
accurately explains it that this is
shorting jurors virus and if you don't
know Chargers cat there's this famous
experiments the wrong word and I didn't
gonna butcher it but that the box with a
cat in it you don't know the cat is
alive or dead and so because you don't
know until you've actually observed it
you the cat is simultaneously alive and
dead
and physicists would would really scoff
at that explanation but whatever that we
all simultaneously have the virus we
have to treat ourselves like we have it
to protect the rest of the world right
we have to like hopefully wear masks
when they go out so if we're coffee and
we're sneezing or just breathing and
we're one of these symptomatic people or
one of the people what's incubating for
14 days we don't spread it to other
people and we simultaneously have to
think we've never had the virus we have
a build of antibodies to not come in
contact with it and keep ourselves and
everyone else safe and so we
simultaneously it's like shorteners
virus we have the virus we have to
assume we both have it and have never
had it had it and that is I mean any
kind of information on an infectious
disease could be helped with data and
can be helped with being able to have
and we are seeing scientists doing this
for this in a way they haven't for other
things but they are coordinating on a
different level where this isn't about
for profit it's about can we get this
vaccine made can we get treatments
passed through and you still have
everyone playing gaming as well so you
have some people there's a company
called Gilead like I'm like did you know
what that was did you name it after
Handmaid's Tale because that seems like
a problematic name but anyway I don't
know why Gilead it's called Gillian ad
maids tale it's probably based on the
same thing but they're they have an
orphan drug and an orphan drug is a drug
that from what I understand because the
toy
a population of people in distributing
areas I don't know what you mean by
disposable devices sorry can we have
disposable devices in these days is that
could help us that we can distribute in
areas distribute what into you mean like
disposable food that we could like drop
into places so they can eat or medical
supplies I mean although medical
supplies are basically disposable maybe
not the respirators but all the stuff
that's connected and gets thrown out and
used for next not used for the next
person generally that's what we're
seeing now is Londoners health I don't
know why I mean maybe to find out I mean
that's that's also part of what any
solution that's happens under gaming
under capitalism in a for-profit model
is although we have a ton of Fitbit
information we only have fit but
information from fairly wealthy
individuals right like I don't know if
it I did it would be a knockoff for sure
so it's not going to concentrate it in
one pool part of it is that we as a
society benefit from people wearing that
and putting their data back into the
system and the individual benefits from
having their own individual data and
there's you know an actual cost to
making that device but all of the profit
that's involved makes it astronomically
expensive if we could produce them at
cost and make them available at cost and
possibly make them available at cost
like a Tom's type model where if I buy
one and it's fifty bucks it actually
buys two of them and it goes to somebody
else who truly can't afford one and then
we have more of the information there's
time there's ton of stuff that keeps
coming out that are our devices that we
can measure stuff on because your blood
pressure you can measure remember there
was one on kick-started that I really
wanted and I don't know if it's still in
existence which is another problem is
these things come and go and they don't
stay in the marketplace because there
isn't enough of the market in order to
keep them anyway the one that you
breathe it into and it would tell you
whether you were digesting your food
properly so it would tell you what you
liked it would tell you if you're gluten
intolerant if you're a dairy intolerant
all of all of this information I had
five or six things that it would it
would measure her but still it's the
kind of thing like am I gonna buy three
hundred dollar device to find that
one time like it's like those are the
kind of things where I want access to it
in a safe way where it's not the same
thing going my mouth is in your mouth
but like at the same time we can share
that like I don't know why we all all
need to have one of those but an orphan
drug is a drug that is for a population
of under 200,000 and I believe the idea
is unlike other drugs which go through a
period of being patent protected that
you can be the only one selling them and
then they except patent expires and then
anyone can make the drug generic so it
can be you know made on mass for a lot
cheaper because people aren't making it
for profit if you are it's there's no
incentive to create a drug for under
200,000 people that you're never gonna
see a profit on because you put in too
much R&D in order to to do that so that
so if your population of people who need
the drug is under 200,000 you don't have
a patent that expires you get to keep
that patent and so Gilead I don't know
which drug it is whether it's the
malaria drug or what it is but they put
in for that before this reached 200,000
in the United States and the wording is
that that's like if you're at you know
195,000 and you got the pack and you get
this time protection for an orphan drug
and then it goes you know 2,500 people
they're not gonna take it away and so
that makes sense for a lot of things
right you have a genetic disorder you
have other things and and it's under
200,000 and it creeps up beyond it but
this thing we knew was gonna be in the
tens of billions hundreds of millions
worldwide and for a company to want to
patent it so that only they can provide
it an American company who clearly isn't
in it for the health and only in it for
the profit because the American
healthcare systems only it for profit
and not for actual health its names
Gilead it's true and I'm like this is
how the patent system gets brought down
like what the people in power right now
are gonna learn but they haven't quite
loaded yet is that this is showing us
how interconnected we are and all the
things that are broken
there is someone suing people are making
3d printed parts for the respirator and
the proof of people who patented the
respirator and how the respirators are
like well we're gonna sue you that is
our in
electril property it's like good luck
existing in the world after this if you
actually do that humanity came together
figure out how to 3d print these things
we can have enough so we can save lives
and if you had been a human
being and been like listen we have to
make it we have to make you know money
enough to stay alive as well so we need
to get 10 cents out of every one that's
printed please keep track of it right
that's a very different than like no you
need to buy them from us for $400 I'm
making up numbers actually is but and
you have to buy them through us and we
can jack up the prices much want or we
can be benevolent and give it to you at
cost you're going to break like you even
can't win that lawsuit not with what's
about to happen and people run to lose
lives and they would have lost even more
lives and gilead it's like if you really
want to go for this patent protection on
this drug you're gonna not just break
that because because Canada better not
hold up hold it Australia better not
uphold it and so you're gonna break the
world patent system because if America
is like yes hundred dollar upheld for
each of your citizens and even if Canada
could afford that India can't China
can't shine again but they won't Hey
like there's we need to be providing
whatever treatment options there are
whatever vaccine options there are we
need to provide it for seven
I need better profit maybe but the
world's doing Oh spirits like a blip I
don't feel like the screen changed but I
don't know how I don't know how it
changed so there's a lot that we could
do if we were able to do it together in
a way that isn't a company like Google
deciding what they're gonna do with our
data and they can't even though they
have all of that information they have
the information of our phones they
understandably can't share that with us
with each other with the government they
might they might because again this is
extraordinary times but we could we
could decide and I don't get to decide
if you want to give your data but if we
have the conversation of what would make
you feel safe enough to give your data
so that you're you have a Fitbit and it
goes back into the system if you have
your genetic information you're willing
to put that in the system so whatever
does happen to you we can find the
common cause right if we can if we have
people's genomes in the system and then
they get koban 19 and the people who
died or the people who are asymptomatic
my guess is there's a genetic component
and we'd be able to tell certain we'd be
able to know are you are you the person
who's gonna be asymptomatic or are you
the people who are gonna die for this
most likely and it won't be perfect data
but it would help us know where we need
to spend our resources covering patients
it's working yeah no I that is one of
one of the treatments for sure I mean it
comes with risks and it comes with a
whole host of other other issues that
are beyond you know health issues like
with any type of blood or gamete donate
donation or organ donation that it needs
to not be for profit right it needs to
be it goes to those who most need it and
not those who have the most money and
guaranteed it will go to those who have
the most money it'll go to the
politicians and the people who can even
if they're not paying for that their
their privilege puts them at the head of
the list and that's less likely to
happen somewhere here like Canada but
it's not it will it'll still happen and
so that you need people who recovered
and then who you give that to because
you need a certain number if you have a
high percentage of the population who
have had this and recovered and can give
give their plasma that they're still
gonna be a short it like you still have
to put the needle in the arm get the
plasma out what's the word manufacture
the plasma make it safer and then put it
in the in the new person there's that's
not it's not scalable without there
being people who've recovered from it
right so we still have to have that
information the data and it is a very
promising thing that's basically what
vaccines do is they give your body like
a training lesson in in fighting the
disease and so that's what this plasma
it's like a pre vaccine like but we
don't know whether just because you've
just bought off Koba 19 how long are you
immune for it could be you know a month
it could be lifetime it could be like we
don't know and it's you're probably
immune until it evolves but how fast is
this thing about and then so how long
after you've had Koba 19 can your plasma
be use how much of your plasma can be
used so that you're still safe right and
you're helping other people and then
like if there is a is a drug because
they also that's not gonna make the
money like you can't really patent
someone's plasma I'm sure they will try
but so that's not actually something
that they're gonna that's not where
they're putting their own t money and
that's probably where dr. is an actual
scientists are like yes let's try this
and it's working so let's let's keep
doing it but you you don't you can't
manufacture that but you could find out
what that is and make that you helped
make you that into a vaccine and help
doing those those things but I mean
we're kind of flying by the seat of our
pants here at 19 when it's like we this
is a drug drug this is a virus that we
don't know there we have been studying
kovat a corona like viruses for a while
but this is on a different level this is
instead of a hypothetical if it crosses
over to humans it's in humans luckily it
only kills one to three percent of the
population because if this thing killed
thirty to forty percent of the
population stayin at home would
like wouldn't work and we it would be
much more devastating it's already going
to be devastating that could be
something that happens it could be
something that that involves and changes
but we can't we can't really fight a
virus right we can come up with vaccines
we can come up with treatments but we
can't annihilate it it's too it's too
far now and we can't like we have to
figure out how to deal with this thing
week it's not and it's this is people
that said this is the new war but it's
also not a war that you can really rally
the troops around in the same old way
that you rally the troops around for
other war right where you had to
dehumanize the enemy the human enemies
already dehumanize it's a virus it's
barely a biology it's by barely alive it
kind of anything you give is a
definition for something being alive
doesn't really apply it to a virus
generally speaking because if it
suggests that it has genetic code you're
dead skin cells have genetic code is it
alive no and it's it's just part of what
breaks biology is viruses the definition
of the species is definitely should have
Alive and so I don't my point that was
except that oh that this is a war that
we have so it's both like bringing
humanity together in a way we never
could before because it's like you can't
really pick sides on this what are you
on the side of the virus you can pick
sides on you think the media's
overhyping and you don't think we should
be taking the projects we are or on the
other side you don't think we're taking
enough precautions but the virus itself
can't be argued with like it does what
it does
you can't like I haven't you only kill
what in a thousand people that'd be
great we'd really like that that would
be closer to the measles and we'd be
very okay with that please kill one and
it's out some people isn't gonna happen
right we can't we can't have a ceasefire
on this we can't argue and so this is
testing all of our other oh we couldn't
possibly do that we can't shut down the
economy for climate change are you
ridiculous we need jobs but we're
shutting it down for a virus and this
virus has a two week time span a meaning
that you see the positive used
to see the positive impact of having
citizens stay inside about two weeks out
because the incubation periods two weeks
and you start seeing the numbers the
percentages of increase is going down so
instead of being 20% increase today it
goes down you know 18% 17% it's still
skyrocketing which is why it's just so
scary about what's happening in America
right now and in Europe and it's just
starting in in a lot of the African
Asian Russia populations that are big
America's not the biggest the most
populous country but it does have more
than double the next one at the moment
when will it be over it won't it won't
be over what over means is like I mean
when someone dies that you love you go
through a period of intense grief and it
gets better but they don't come back and
you never fully recover from that that
is what we were going through we will be
come to a new normal we'll figure out
what our new normal is but if we won't
all be locked inside we don't like we
won't all be inside not be able to touch
anyone ever our population will go away
because how are you gonna date and have
babies if that's the case but we might
never go back to having 250 people
gatherings like your wedding it might be
50 people from now on or you're gonna
kill our grandparents I don't like it's
like or we reverse course and like we
flatten the curve enough we allow for
the sacrifice but this this isn't a
one-off we've been really lucky to not
have a pandemic so far and with climate
change with people with the disparity of
wealth in the world you have a lot of
people who are desperate for things that
they get from what markets both the
money and also the the idea that that
because in the wet markets in China
aren't really for us assistants living
and it's not because they're like
importing animals and then having them
there for the pet trade and for the new
trade and but they
the desperation that comes into that be
needed is is part of the problem and as
soon as as long as those are happening
there's gonna be more of a chance for
crossover as long as we have animals at
all that are that are factory farm
there's going to be chance to cross over
and with the climate change going up our
temperature as our temperature increases
everything it's more exasperated we're
more likely to have a crossover so these
are warmer more chemical reactions and
when there's a crossover it's more
likely to to go global this one happens
to be perfect for what it's for what
it's doing the fact it had is the fact
there's asymptomatic people you can
spread it the fact that it takes a
really long time where you're also
spreading it for you to know you're even
sick if you're on asymptomatic and the
fact that it's deadly but not extremely
deadly this is both the perfect fight
like if you were mother like you could
design this virus to be like I want it
to go pandemic this would be the type of
one cuz people didn't really take it
seriously you can have two sides to this
there isn't really two sides to Ebola
it's not like oh you overhyped Ebola
know most people die who get a bola but
the results of extreme precautions taken
everyone gave aid to Africa when they
were going through it so that they could
deal with it not out of the goodness of
their heart because they didn't want it
to spread to everywhere in the world and
Ebola is something that's hard to
transmit you basically have to come in
contact with somebody's bodily fluids
generally their I believe like it's
like very and yet that's happening as
people are having horrible symptoms in
when they have it that from a disease
perspective we again we can't reason
with it it's just for Biological beings
and it is what it's happening and
because we can't reason with it we can't
argue our way out of it we have to shut
down our economies and so how important
our economies there's real pieces to
them we need food we need people to feel
like they matter
we need people's mental health and
emotional health to be taken care of we
need you know to be able to have access
to goods that we rely on embedded
send me rely on but there's also a large
part of our part of our economic system
that is absolutely useless and gives no
amount of value and then there's there's
parts of every corporation that are like
that that are just kind of like tacked
on jobs what are in oxygen you're saying
that those things are important those
things are important but that is I think
this thing's how possible is your -
pandemic I'm giving you like the
apocalypse during the Pens I made sorry
about that cuz mmm this thing isn't
gonna go away we will find a new normal
and that new normal can be better than
anything we've ever had we don't need to
go back like our human psyche kind of
only knows what we give up and so the
fact that we can't go to Starbucks the
fact that we can't have our sporting
teams the fact that we are weddings got
canceled my kid just found out her camp
got camo is probably gonna be cancelled
this summer - look what I can't go to
camp it's like yeah probably not this is
gonna be a pause a year and then we'll
have to reevaluate like camp will still
exist next year probably but things like
Coachella things like Bernie man might
not exist ever again we can't have more
than you know 250 300 people getting
together because that's what Bahamas
spread and it's probably gonna become
the flu where it's just everywhere all
the time and so having a bunch of people
congregated is always gonna spread and
we're always gonna have these these huge
but also our immune systems will once
we've had it once we'll know better how
to how to prepare for it the next time
in two months it will be over I mean
there's a slight chance that there's
something we don't understand about it
where it does just disappear a lot of
pandemics in the past have just
disappeared but that's because they kind
of burned through the population and
what we're trying to do is slap the
curve because unlike in 1918 when the
Spanish flu went through um one of the
reasons it became appends emic was cause
of World War two and people ship you
know it all over the world and and just
the reason it's called the Spanish flu
is because Spain at the time wasn't
involved in the war and so they they
were the only ones taking data and
information because no one else wanted
to give the information for the enemy to
find
they all have the flu so every side of
the army had the flu Spain was just the
ones who gave that up yeah
they probably did disappear through herd
immunity that's kind of how we fight
biological is this way but if what
we do is come up with a vaccine which
also kind of gives hurt immunity then
we're not we're finding an enemy who
wins the arms race it's really what
we're doing because it's not just about
kovat 19 although it's taken a hundred
years to get our next huge pandemic that
we've got this far like the Spanish flu
our next one isn't a hundred years out
our next ones next year a decade from
now like it's not this thing will keep
happening until we repair our planet and
get our our bodies but better with
proper nutrition and those are the
things we can be doing I mean I have
very little say on how the virus is
gonna run out very little say and of
course how our governments are gonna run
it I can only I'm someone who does not
listen to our powers that be just to
listen to our powers to be I question
everything and I will be staying at home
during this and I also get the other
side where they're like they're gonna
take away our rights and we're just
letting them and I'm like well we're
also on our entropy like on internet at
home and I know we can have a more
powerful revolution from our tablets and
desktops then marching out in the street
because marching out in the street
didn't really do much all you're doing
is demanding your governments do
something about whatever right about
climate change about women's rights
about pro-life pro-choice whatever it
happens to be that you care about you're
demanding that your governments do what
you want them to do they don't actually
know what to do so even if they listened
they actually don't know what to do we
have to figure out a system where we can
figure out what could be done and not in
smaller experiments and be like okay
well we're gonna try this and feed that
information back into the systems in
both kovat 19 and food and plumbing and
everything this is
last pet if we lose freedom to our data
right I mean it wouldn't be the last
pandemic I'm people ask without rights
intact
yeah governments all over the world are
becoming more authoritarian right now
but a large part of that it's like all
of my friends or conspiracy theorists
and all the people who are like they're
gonna take our rights away I'm like yes
and you're giving them every opportunity
to if people listen and stay at home
right now they have there's no way they
could have the are the military involved
policing people out in the streets if
people were actually at home because
people aren't at home then they go to
let's why what LGBT people disappear
because there's no merchants exactly we
were all just doing it for the parade
and now there's no parades I don't know
and that like a lot of our big cultural
celebrations are huge if we can't go
back to that it sounds devastating at
the same time having 50 to 100 people
tiny celebrations all over the place
people are invited to creating community
and connection in a way we've never had
it before is possible and so everyone
can still have a very fulfilling life
even though we're never going to go back
to normal
it's just weather weather our new normal
is a fascist dictatorship where we all
have to listen to our government a
hundred percent of the time and we have
no way of banding together and taking
back our power and they probably
cancelled our internet or we can go to a
world of we can learn from this and
realize if anyone's in poverty it's
gonna cost us all if we lose anyone we
lose that we lose their their potential
to give back to the world and that costs
us all that people don't have access to
health care costs us all and so we can
those of us who want to can participate
in creating a better world together
where everyone is taken care of and that
everyone can be internal and we just
keep inviting more and more people so
that's what the solution regimes are is
how do we create a solution that we
would want for 10,000
people who each put in $10 therefore we
have $100,000 and once we've created a
solution for them everyone's invited if
we create a new platform we will be for
the 10,000 people that's enough of a
threshold to make it usable most of the
things that are being done don't have a
threshold of 10,000 people so they fall
away because they can't be funded and
it's not fun to hang out on it's saying
that there isn't enough people on
animals will be freed from circuses oh I
see because we won't be going to them I
was like they're nothing is gonna set
all the animals free that sounds like
lions and tigers out of the streets yes
yes I would say I mean at least in North
America most of those things already
have been shut down for animal rights
reasons for a long time but even
circuses like service de Soleil yeah
what's it gonna be pissed I don't know
anything that's big like that like even
going to the movie theatre is like 250
people that's probably our limit is the
movie theater so anything bigger than
that but that's I'm not the one making
rules and so maybe we come if we come up
with a vaccine that lasts it gives you
life long or 10-year immunity then
whatever thing I said goes by the
wayside but if this is the flu and we
need a new one every year we're never
going to be able to the reason the flu
vaccine works is enough people get it
and it's not deadly and like it's it
doesn't work when the death rate is
higher says I will move to normal copa90
mo mutate itself that you think things
will remove you know you think things go
back to normal because copa90 mutates
cuz that's not a that's from my
understanding of biology and I am a
biologist by my trade at university
that's not possible
but science also doesn't take into they
who they like don't like the deal with
the impossible so they just ignore it so
I mean that is what has happened with
the several of the pandemic
and epidemics that have went through the
human population as we do develop herd
immunity we do develop those things but
that'll take a long time and like I said
this is not a one-off this is gonna keep
happening we're different we won't know
what the next one is right the next
one's not going to be a respiratory
illness that that waits for two weeks
and has a cement Ematic people and you
have to wear a mask and you like all you
have to do is wash your hands it could
be airborne it could be it could be have
a even longer incubation period it could
be even more deadly it could be not a
respiratory thing so all the respirators
we have stacked up have no no effective
effectiveness the face shields might not
be the thing we use like there's the
face shields actually are almost always
use that the like n95 masks might not be
the thing that helps the next the next
kind of it and so we have to be able to
create the systems not just for pandemic
but for all of the chaos that's coming
down the line all the natural disasters
all of the let's get away with war it's
just get rid of it because we really
don't need it and we're dealing with
everything else but again we don't have
the power to necessarily do that we do
have the power to create solutions that
we want to be part of and then invite
the rest of the world to so we can
figure out our food system right now in
a way that doesn't rely on the very
complex fragile food chain we currently
have and everywhere we should be
thinking about that because at least
where I am it's it's April yeah well
it's April everywhere but it's
spring-like that's just yours to know
that's for you my country where most
people should have their gardens in
already if they're gonna have a garden
I'm not one of those people and so the
idea of herd immunity is absolutely not
verified it's just a mathematical model
it's a it's like something that makes
sense but has it been tested and
verified no no no NASA and in fact a lot
of what we saw before the measles
vaccine measles was when I smallpox
might have also been one you see the
morality mortality rate go down to
almost zero meaning people were still
absolutely getting it
they just weren't dying from it and then
the vaccine was
introduced and you have a lot more a lot
less people getting it understandably
because there's a vaccine and morality
mortality rate from what I know say the
same but we you don't pass your
vaccinated status on to your children
you do pass your immunity on to them
both because they have your genetics and
you survives but also milks weird milk
it in utero like the whole immune system
is absolutely crazy in it ya know there
is like if you survive if you're
susceptible you die and if you survive
and you're helping with herd immunity
but that's different than if again if
this is something we can find a vaccine
for and it's like the measles where you
just need to get a booster every ten
years then we could fight this one with
a vaccine but not the next one and what
do we like I flew twice during this
pandemic and I never fly but I flew from
Vancouver Edmonton and went into
Vancouver and I was astounded that there
was no like me my kid have had a cough
since January and so we're coffee no one
has asked us if we had it no one's like
could you wear a mask they don't test
your temperature they don't do they're
not doing anything no screening and
coming back same thing I was like this
is ridiculous actually like we we're
gonna need a new normal just like 9/11
changed our airports immensely so that
you know you can't bring more than 100
milliliters of a liquid on a plane it's
like you can't get on a plane if you
have a fever and we test absolutely
everyone and if you're someone who
constantly runs a fever for other
reasons you need to have a medical note
dictating that and we need to have
information that is reliable or when
someone's been sick on a plane that
information goes out to all of the
people who are on that plane and they
sell quarantine and we have the systems
in place to help themselves warranty
because that's the other thing that this
is showcasing people can't always do the
right thing just because you want them
to do the right thing and what is the
right thing they when when our response
to this is go home and self quarantine
for two weeks we found in any
understanding of how someone does that
when they don't have groceries
how somebody does that when they need
medication we and the government doesn't
know how to respond to that and so where
people have taken that out people are
like okay the senior citizens you can't
leave because they're they're more
susceptible there's people who are
quarantine Ian for the good of our
health who what do they do they need
food at home they need to have who can
coordinate that effort and those are the
things we should be doing and that might
be where this does not go back to normal
the fact that you could go to you could
fly across the world for a week you
could fly across the world for a weekend
as long as you had the money to do it
there used to be quarantined right when
that was mean we were on ships when you
would cross the ocean and before
vaccines we need quarantines again which
means you don't just get to go tricks
about the globe for the fun of it have a
freaking zoom call for business and if
you really want to do something like go
to Paris or go to Australia or go to
Machu Picchu
you have to quarantine for two weeks
before you go and two weeks on the other
end that's a month so you better make it
worth it is it gonna be like
once-in-a-lifetime trips five times in a
lifetime trips you're not gonna be in
New York one day Paris the next day
Beijing the next day because we want to
keep safe we'll be in more insulated
communities where you are with 300 maybe
a thousand people and the community
itself makes you self foreign to you
right so maybe in the big cities they
don't do that maybe you don't have to
self quarantine people aren't traipsing
around the globe but there'll be smaller
communities where they're like no you
need to give us your entire itinerary
over the last month and we need to be
able to actually believe it honey heist
what was I remember sorry I did not read
your stuff the last of it
still I just need more to understand how
nature behaves there a lot of buyers is
out there yeah and that's the other the
group of the ice caps melting somehow is
is releasing whole new ones that have
been dormant for literally under ice for
hundreds of years and our bodies have no
idea
how to deal with those at least the
animal species we could kind of study in
there I mean kind of study Wachovia does
in bats if we probably wanted to before
I'd ever hit humans the issue is you
can't like study all of them to the same
the same degree my kid is being loud but
I don't yet know quite what these hours
are gonna look like I as I said I posted
the link in the description and on
Twitter so anyone can join on video if
they want I've been doing solution
raisings we've done six of them would
come six amazing solutions and that was
only over a six-hour period that was
like an hour for education an hour for
food an hour for transportation hour for
infectious disease and three to five of
us are able to come up with amazing
solutions in that time period that could
be implemented right now and so what I
want to do during this time is either
showcase those showcase what those look
like online so do them live do one on
mental health do you want ANCOVA 19 do
you want on any of the things that
people wants to talk about then they're
neat I can't do them by myself I needs
to do other people on camera but what I
really want is the people who want to
have the meta conversation so not just
come up with a solution for food not
just come up with a solution for
transportation but to come up with a
solution for how we come up with
solutions so solution raising is the
first part of that because we're able to
generate potential ideas in an hour and
it's and it's scalable like you can have
it's scalable right now to a hundred to
five hundred right like I can deal with
five hundred people that week on zoom'
calls and we could raise education from
the week we could have you know a
hundred different conversations five
people in each conversation where we
were generating a hundred different
possible outcomes and then vote on which
one we like the best and then the next
week help improve that one but what we
need to do eventually is get to 10,000
people so what Jordan Holland say
yesterday and I agree I think this is a
good is to find a system that works for
a thousand people to create a solution
together and then have each of those
thousand go out and bite and buy ten and
that's where I differ in a lot of what
everyone else wants to do I don't need
the elite of society to come and come
and do this I need everyday people to
come and do this ever
one has something to give everyone has
an opinion everyone brings their own
life experience to the team it's about
finding out how we can work together at
that level at the 7.5 billion people
level not leaving solutions up to our
governments working with 7.5 billion
people is next to impossible so we're
gonna figure it out for a thousand and
then we're going to invite 10 people
each and then we'll be at 10,000 see you
said by us you're probably already gone
but I made a bakery that if there were
three to four of us here live not
everyday because everyone else doesn't
need to commit to an hour but basically
we're just gonna host a revolution
during an hour a day so you can show up
and be part of the revolution for an
hour you can miss a few days once
there's somebody who's able to take
notes and able to say because this is
don't take notes right now this is just
me rambling for an hour well we're
trying to figure out like what does this
look like how can we actually create a
better world together during these this
hour every day it's its solution raising
is how but it's like once we have the
idea during the hour how do we move
forward with it how do we have more than
five people participate and have dozens
and hundreds of people participate I
have ideas for all of that but unless we
generate it together there isn't going
to be the the energy and ingenuity
behind it to actually put it into place
and that is the point is coming up with
solutions together we have the energy
together we have the will of if you have
10,000 people co-creating a solution
it's not going to work for all 10,000 of
them but if you can figure out a
solution that works for nine thousand up
to ten thousand and then you can invite
the world and 90% of the world will be
benefited by coming and the 10% that
isn't benefit and can find a new
solution that works for them and they're
able to find 7,000 people and we were
able to work through how envisioning it
right now is something like a contest
that the payoff is that you get to
participate in the contest which there's
tons of right like I mean people pay to
be part of a scavenger hunt to the city
or to be part of a coating for good good
campaign and so the idea is anyone can
participate what does that look like and
it looks like 10,000 people this is
again my vision we haven't come up with
it together yet but
and thousand people who are contributing
money to the problem and contributing
votes unlike what they would like and
not like in it but they're not probably
part of the conversation they're like at
the very big periphery of those 10,000
maybe a thousand people are having the
actual conversation if 10,000 people
want to have the conversation we need to
make it for 10,000 people but the point
is to meet people where they are and not
force anyone to do what they don't want
to do so just give him ten dollars to
the cause is more than enough just
voting on things so we know we're making
it for you is enough then you have the
people having the actual very
conversation then you have maybe a
hundred people doing more work doing the
organizing doing the facilitation and
doing in each individual one and
communicating what would make it easier
and what would make it better and then
you have maybe ten people out of that
10,000 working full time being the board
of directors moving it forward and that
is what I want to do online it is like
that piece is having the conversation
with other people who can see the
potential in solution raising and how
can humanity come together and create
solutions that we want to be part of we
want to have and again we came up with
six different ones using the six hours
that if I would sign I would give $10 to
a month to each and every one of these
causes and that's not even a model the
model is to give $10 to it one time to
create $100,000 some of them might need
$10 one and we'll figure that out let's
do that part like education right now
again this was a pre kovin world where
we came up the education one but if we
had the possibility of anything you want
to learn it already exists out there
just finding the right one for your
learning style and putting the plethora
of information that's available into
like a course write a more succinct
here's now you know you know county
because you took this course for your
learning style and so the educate that
about the potential for education we
came up with was to organize that was to
have people be able to put together
courses with existing material and have
it more home to your learning style in
your specific interest so if I want my
kids to learn math I can search
minecraft in math because she likes
minecraft and I'll find things that are
more likely to appeal
her and then having of course away to
track it's your own tasks so it's like
game a fide and you can find start your
own talents your own traits and whether
you're improving out them and how to
improve about them for food there's so
much we could do for food with you with
technology
I mean having an app right now that
doesn't matter how inept you are at
gardening you could put in a garden
here's where you get the seeds you know
this is from Google Maps we know where
your your property is because you've
told us and we know where Sun sets and
where Sun Sun Goes Down we know that
there was a big tree there we know where
shade is and we know where light is we
know the temperature we can tell you
went to water when there's an issue with
weeds or insects or mold you can take a
picture and have experts help you want
it there was again pre koban nineteen
seems a little less important but having
both buying with your neighbors be able
to do things like like cook
cooperatively so you have less time put
into the system but you're still getting
good nutritious food up for less and
less input into the system and one app
could do all that recipe sharing so you
can know what's in what's in season in
your area that it's five bucks a portion
that you know that this historic that's
right there carries all of it all of the
goods that you need to be able to buy it
there's a lot we can do together there's
so much we can do together whatever is
our solution we're gonna be more likely
to to trust it and more likely to input
our our thoughts and ideas right we want
to improve it cuz we're the user we want
it to be what we need it to be instead
of making it so that someone else can
profit off of it right so that Google
can make more money even if they're
giving us tools that we want we can have
the best of both worlds we can have a
technology company that is more powerful
than any technology company that's ever
done because we can trust it and because
we can we can create tools that we need
to use and it'll be less risky than it's
any other startup because creating
technology with ten thousand people each
putting in ten dollars nobody's at a
high risk everyone can lose ten dollars
and still be okay no one's gonna be on
their deathbed I can't believe if I
invested in that - a gun it's like no we
try again even if we fail
it's like what $10 gone let's do it
again what did we learn how can you
create it again and I don't think we do
fail because if even if you have a beta
of something beta just means like a
preliminary
something that's like the basic basic
features you would need it to be to make
it usable and then it keeps improving
it'll get better and better I'm getting
all over the place for infectious
disease we talked about being able to
share our dad I've been able to see what
different cohorts that have chosen to be
part of that cohort or doing so instead
of having a scientific study where your
placebo and your your treatment and
we're gonna study that is a better study
for science but I'm not a guinea pig I'm
not a lab rat I'm not gonna do what you
tell me to do I'm just gonna live my
life and I'll give my data to it so you
can see whether or not I get cope at 19
if I do get it how impacted am I and
again you can't know that what I can't
know with what I'm doing is having an
impact unless I have the population
otherwise it's just so we're speculation
it's a one-person story I camera for the
word from that is but we need
populations of information to be able to
know what is itself of this I'm
realizing I'm now at the hour that was
an hour so I will be back tomorrow we
are going to have an ever live
revolution today that I'm gonna go try
and live my life and clean my house and
hang out with my kid outside of that and
outside of the other things we're doing
we're also on the together tech YouTube
channel we go live every every Friday at
noon because that's our together Tech
movie for the tech cooperative itself
and we're focusing more on the meta meta
project because everyone has their own
individual baby pet project and nobody
kind of wants to give up their own
project and work on one big one so we're
bringing our projects to it and saying
what could we create that could help
bring all of these into the world and
then working from from that side and my
baby project is solution raising is like
how do we bring the masses to actually
work on a problem together what can that
look like and right now that looks like
having an hour-long conversation with
three to five people but as soon as
there's enough people who want to
participate we can be hosting them on
zoom' so people don't need to have their
video broadcast lives the world if that
doesn't make them comfortable
and then we can work through how do we
collect that information how do we
collect the ideas from 100 different
conversations what it tools are out
there to best be able to vote on which
one we like the most this isn't a it
doesn't actually matter which one wins
because we're all going to participate
in creating it and making it better so
it's all of ours when it's when it's
done and then how do we actually fund it
how do we actually and again my vision
is ten thousand people put in ten
dollars and we get to 100,000 that
doesn't necessarily mean that's what we
actually do we might have grant money we
might have someone who's just a really
rich person who wants to put in a lot
more money to be able to say like this
is for the good of humanity if this is
what we were concentrating our money and
time on right now we would emerge into a
whole new world and so that is what I'm
concentrating my time and money into so
when we emerge into a world that's never
going to go back to normal but we can
have everybody be fed we can have
everyone have a safe beautiful housing
and clothing that is their own personal
style that's durable that's not fast
fashion we can you know have
transportation of goods and we can have
a world where everyone's able to live
their purpose and their genius and we
all get to benefit from that where
everyone has a place and a community in
connection because we didn't let people
fall through the cracks there's no one
who is into worthy human being who's not
worthy of connection and life and and
liberty and all that all that good stuff
and so if we can come together and
create a system where our governments
can't take over because although we
can't leave our houses and we can't pour
out into the streets and have a
revolution right now that'd be the worst
time to do that we are on our computers
we're connected like never before and we
can have a revolution from our living
rooms we can have a lot revolution from
our from our bedrooms in our pajamas we
just need to have the conversations of
what it is we want to create together
and then have the conversate the bigger
got a conversation of like how do we
actually create that process so that it
goes from idea to to thing in the world
and so that is what we are going to be
doing here and that's what I'm doing
interests in the world all day every day
so thanks for hanging out and I'll see
you tomorrow